<outline text="Familiar and Unfamiliar Quotations">
</outline>
<outline text="About &lt;a href=&quot;http://norvig.com/quotations.html#life&quot;&gt;Life&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://norvig.com/quotations.html#universe&quot;&gt;The Universe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://norvig.com/quotations.html#computers&quot;&gt;Computers,&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://norvig.com/quotations.html#everything&quot;&gt;Everything&lt;/a&gt;" _note="------------------------------------------------------------------------&#10;&#10;[TABLE]&#10;&#10;Always do right. This will gratify some people and astonish the rest.  &#10;*    - [Mark Twain](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mark_twain)*&#10;&#10;A man is a success if he gets up in the morning and gets to bed at&#10;night, and in between he does what he wants to do.  &#10;*    - [Bob Dylan](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bob_Dylan)*&#10;&#10;Don't wait for the Last Judgement. It takes place every day.  &#10;*    - [Albert Camus](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Camus)*&#10;&#10;Brick walls are there for a reason. They're not there to keep us out.&#10;The brick walls are there to give us a chance to show how badly we want&#10;something.  &#10;*    - [Randy Pausch](http://randypausch.com/)*&#10;&#10;Far and away the best prize life has to offer is the chance to work hard&#10;at work worth doing.  &#10;*    - [Theodore&#10;Roosevelt](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Theodore_Roosevelt)*&#10;&#10;I cannot afford to waste my time making money.  &#10;*    - [Louis Agassiz](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Louis_Agassiz)*&#10;&#10;All you have to decide is what you're going to do with the time you are&#10;given.  &#10;*    - [Gandalf](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gandalf)*&#10;&#10;The quality of a person's life is in direct proportion to their&#10;commitment to excellence, regardless of their field of endeavor.  &#10;*    - [Vince Lombardi](http://www.vincelombardi.com/)*&#10;&#10;No art, however minor, demands less than total dedication if you want to&#10;excel in it.  &#10;*    - [Leon Battista&#10;Alberti](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leone_Battista_Alberti),&#10;(architect, painter and mathematician)*&#10;&#10;My crystal ball is fuzzy  &#10;*    - [Lotfi&#10;Zadeh](http://www.cs.berkeley.edu/People/Faculty/Homepages/zadeh.html)&#10;(inventor of Fuzzy Logic, when asked to predict the future)*&#10;&#10;If I had a dollar for every million-dollar idea I've had, I'd be rich.  &#10;*    - [Greg Meyer](http://www.compliancemedia.com/Principals.html)*&#10;&#10;There's nothing that will change someone's moral outlook quicker than&#10;cash in large sums.  &#10;*    - [Larry Flynt](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Larry_Flynt)*&#10;&#10;The perfect is the enemy of the good.  &#10;*    - [Voltaire](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Voltaire)*&#10;&#10;I have great faith in fools. Self-confidence, my friends call it.  &#10;*    - [Edgar Allen Poe](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edgar_Allan_Poe)*&#10;&#10;The point of all this is to be able to spend more time at the beach!  &#10;*    - [Nils&#10;Nilsson](http://robotics.stanford.edu/users/nilsson/bio.html)*&#10;&#10;Being famous has its benefits, but fame isn't one of them.  &#10;*    - [Larry Wall](http://www.wall.org/~larry/)*&#10;&#10;Personally, I liked the university. They gave us money and facilities,&#10;we didn't have to produce anything! You've never been out of college!&#10;You don't know what it's like out there! I've *worked* in the private&#10;sector. They expect *results*.  &#10;*    - [Dr Ray Stanz (Dan&#10;Aykroyd)](http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000101/), Ghostbusters*&#10;&#10;A great many people think they are thinking when they are merely&#10;rearranging their prejudices.  &#10;*    - [William James](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_James)*&#10;&#10;It is the mark of an educated mind to be able to entertain a thought&#10;without accepting it.  &#10;*    - [Aristotle](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aristotle)*&#10;&#10;I try to leave out the parts that people skip.  &#10;*    - [Elmore Leonard](http://en.wikipedia.org/Elmore_Leonard) (on his&#10;secret to writing)*&#10;&#10;Either write something worth reading or do something worth writing.  &#10;*    - [Benjamin&#10;Franklin](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benjamin_Franklin)*&#10;&#10;Believe, if thou wilt, that mountains change their place, but believe&#10;not that man changes his nature.  &#10;*    - [Mohammed](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mohammed)*&#10;&#10;[TABLE]&#10;&#10;In the beginning, the Universe was created. This has made a lot of&#10;people very angry and been widely regarded as a bad move.  &#10;*    - [Douglas Adams](http://www.douglasadams.com/)*&#10;&#10;Space isn't remote at all. It's only an hour's drive away if your car&#10;could go straight upwards.  &#10;*    - [Fred Hoyle](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fred_Hoyle)*&#10;&#10;Man is the best computer we can put aboard a spacecraft... and the only&#10;one that can be mass produced with unskilled labor.  &#10;*    - [Wernher von&#10;Braun](http://liftoff.msfc.nasa.gov/academy/history/vonBraun/vonBraun.html)*&#10;&#10;We can lick gravity, but sometimes the paperwork is overwhelming.  &#10;*    - [Wernher von&#10;Braun](http://liftoff.msfc.nasa.gov/academy/history/vonBraun/vonBraun.html)*&#10;&#10;I don't see any god up here.  &#10;*    - [Yuri Gagarin](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gagarin) (in orbit,&#10;1961)*&#10;&#10;Only two things are infinite, the universe and human stupidity, and I'm&#10;not sure about the former.  &#10;*    - [Albert Einstein](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Einstein)*&#10;&#10;There are 10¹¹ stars in the galaxy. That used to be a *huge* number. But&#10;it's only a hundred billion. It's less than the national deficit! We&#10;used to call them astronomical numbers. Now we should call them&#10;economical numbers.  &#10;*    - [Richard Feynman](http://www.feynmanonline.com/)*&#10;&#10;For all our conceits about being the center of the universe, we live in&#10;a routine planet of a humdrum star stuck away in an obscure corner ...&#10;on an unexceptional galaxy which is one of about 100 billion galaxies.&#10;... That is the fundamental fact of the universe we inhabit, and it is&#10;very good for us to understand that.  &#10;*    - [Carl Sagan](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carl_Sagan)*&#10;&#10;Far out in the uncharted backwaters of the unfashionable end of the&#10;Western Spiral arm of the Galaxy lies a small unregarded yellow sun.&#10;Orbiting this at a distance of roughly ninety-eight million miles is an&#10;utterly insignificant little blue-green planet whose ape-descended life&#10;forms are so amazingly primitive that they still think digital watches&#10;are a pretty neat idea.  &#10;*    - [Douglas Adams](http://www.douglasadams.com/)*&#10;&#10;[TABLE]&#10;&#10;Some software is actually pretty good, by any standard. Think of the&#10;Mars Rovers, Google, and the Human Genome Project. Now, that's quality&#10;software!  &#10;*    - [Bjarne Stroustrup](http://parasol.tamu.edu/people/bs/), (when&#10;asked by [Technology&#10;Review](http://www.technologyreview.com/Infotech/17987/?a=f) &quot;Why is&#10;software so bad?&quot;. I'm proud to have worked on two of those three&#10;projects.)*&#10;&#10;The world has arrived at an age of cheap complex devices of great&#10;reliability; and something is bound to come of it.  &#10;*    - [Vannevar Bush](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vannevar_Bush)&#10;(1945)*&#10;&#10;Power corrupts, and obsolete power corrupts obsoletely.  &#10;*    - [Ted Nelson](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ted_Nelson), on the&#10;Microsoft DOS operating system*&#10;&#10;Computers make it easier to do a lot of things, but most of the things&#10;they make it easier to do don't need to be done  &#10;*    - [Andy Rooney](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andy_Rooney)*&#10;&#10;As soon as we started programming, we found out to our surprise that it&#10;wasn't as easy to get programs right as we had thought. Debugging had to&#10;be discovered. I can remember the exact instant when I realized that a&#10;large part of my life from then on was going to be spent in finding&#10;mistakes in my own programs.  &#10;*    - [Maurice Wilkes](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maurice_Wilkes)*&#10;&#10;Only wimps use tape backup: *real* men just upload their important stuff&#10;on ftp, and let the rest of the world mirror it.  &#10;*    - [Linus Torvalds](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linus_Torvalds)*&#10;&#10;C++ is history repeated as tragedy. Java is history repeated as farce.  &#10;*    - [Scott McKay](mailto:swm@mediaone.net)*&#10;&#10;Nothing is destroyed until it is replaced.  &#10;*    - [Auguste Comte&#10;(1798-1857)](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Auguste_Comte) (on the need&#10;for revolutionary new theories (or on the need to do `x.f = null` in&#10;garbage-collected languages with destructors))*&#10;&#10;In general, they do what you want, unless you want consistency.  &#10;*    - [Larry Wall](http://www.wall.org/~larry/) (on Perl functions)*&#10;&#10;Computer language design is just like a stroll in the park. Jurassic&#10;Park, that is.  &#10;*    - [Larry Wall](http://www.wall.org/~larry/)*&#10;&#10;If you give someone Fortran, he has Fortran. If you give someone Lisp,&#10;he has any language he pleases.  &#10;*    - [Guy L. Steele](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guy_Steele)*&#10;&#10;\[Lisp\] is the only computer language that is beautiful.  &#10;*    - [Neal Stephenson](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neal_Stephenson)*&#10;&#10;If you can't hear me, it's because I'm in parentheses.  &#10;*    - [Steven Wright](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steven_Wright)*&#10;&#10;He who refuses to do arithmetic is doomed to talk nonsense.  &#10;*    - [John McCarthy](http://www-formal.stanford.edu/jmc/)*&#10;&#10;Belief is no substitute for arithmetic.  &#10;*    - [Henry Spencer](http://www.lysator.liu.se/c/henry/)*&#10;&#10;Object-oriented programming is an exceptionally bad idea which could&#10;only have originated in California.  &#10;*    - [Edsger&#10;Dijkstra](http://www.cs.utexas.edu/users/UTCS/report/1994/profiles/dijkstra.html)&#10;(attributed)*&#10;&#10;We read Knuth so you don't have to.  &#10;*    -[Tim Peters](http://c2.com/cgi/wiki?TimPeters) (explaining what&#10;the Python developers do in their spare time)*&#10;&#10;Computers are useless. They can only give you answers.  &#10;*    - [Pablo Picasso](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Picasso)*&#10;&#10;I do not believe in objects. I believe only in their relationships.  &#10;*    - [George Braque](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Braque)*&#10;&#10;I don't paint things. I only paint the difference between things.  &#10;*    - [Henri Matisse](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matisse)*&#10;&#10;Mathematicians do not study objects, but relations among objects; they&#10;are indifferent to the replacement of objects by others as long the&#10;relations don't change. Matter is not important, only form interests&#10;them.  &#10;*    - [Henri&#10;Poincare](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Henri_Poincar%C3%A9)*&#10;&#10;Have nothing in your houses that you do not know to be useful, or&#10;believe to be beautiful.  &#10;*    - [William Morris](http://www.morrissociety.org/)*&#10;&#10;All models are wrong. Some models are useful.  &#10;*    - [George&#10;Box](http://www.engr.wisc.edu/ie/faculty/box_george.html)*&#10;&#10;When cryptography is outlawed, bayl bhgynjf jvyy unir cevinpl!  &#10;*    - [Brad Templeton](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brad_Templeton)*&#10;&#10;Errors using inadequate data are much less than those using no data at&#10;all.  &#10;*    - [Charles Babbage](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Babbage)*&#10;&#10;In the future, search engines should be as useful as HAL in the movie&#10;*2001: A Space Odyssey*--but hopefully they won't kill people.  &#10;*    - [Sergey Brin](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sergey_Brin)*&#10;&#10;[TABLE]&#10;&#10;Doubt is not a pleasant condition, but certainty is an absurd one.  &#10;*    - [Voltaire](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Voltaire)*&#10;&#10;There are three principal ways to lose money: wine, women, and&#10;engineers. While the first two are more pleasant, the third is by far&#10;the more certain.  &#10;*    - [Baron Rothschild](http://www.jewishpeople.net/barrot.html)*&#10;&#10;God is a hacker, not an engineer.  &#10;*    - [Francis Crick](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Francis_Crick)*&#10;&#10;You can do reverse engineering, but you can't do reverse hacking.  &#10;*    - [V. S.&#10;Ramachandran](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vilayanur_S._Ramachandran)*&#10;&#10;I have often thought that if there had been a good rap group in those&#10;days, I might have chosen a career in music instead of politics.  &#10;*    - [Richard Nixon](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nixon)*&#10;&#10;If I have made myself clear, you must have misunderstood me.  &#10;*    - [Alan Greenspan](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greenspan)*&#10;&#10;Science is like sex: sometimes something useful comes out, but that is&#10;not the reason we are doing it  &#10;*    - [Richard Feynman](http://www.feynmanonline.com/)*&#10;&#10;Literature is mostly about having sex, and not much about having babies;&#10;life is the other way round.  &#10;*    - [David&#10;Lodge](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Lodge_%28author%29)*&#10;&#10;More than any other time in history mankind faces a crossroads. One path&#10;leads to despair and utter hopelessness, the other to total extinction.&#10;Let us pray we have the wisdom to choose correctly.  &#10;*    -[Woody Allen](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Woody_Allen)*&#10;&#10;When you have eliminated the impossible, whatever remains, however&#10;improbable, must be the truth.  &#10;*    - [Sir Arthur Conan&#10;Doyle](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arthur_Conan_Doyle)*&#10;&#10;Chance favors only the prepared mind.  &#10;*    - [Louis Pasteur](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pasteur)*&#10;&#10;Lord, give us the wisdom to utter words that are gentle and tender, for&#10;tomorrow we may have to eat them.  &#10;*    -[Sen. Morris Udall](http://www.udall.gov/mku.htm)*&#10;&#10;It does not require a majority to prevail, but rather an irate, tireless&#10;minority keen to set brush fires in people's minds.  &#10;*    - [Samuel Adams](http://www.samadams.com/)*&#10;&#10;I don't want to achieve immortality through my work ... I want to&#10;achieve it through not dying.  &#10;*    - [Woody Allen](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Woody_allen)*&#10;&#10;I am a man of fixed and unbending principles, the first of which is to&#10;be flexible at all times.  &#10;*    - [Sen. Everett Dirksen](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dirksen)*&#10;&#10;When I face an issue of great import that cleaves both constituents and&#10;colleagues, I always take the same approach. I engage in deep&#10;deliberation and quiet contemplation. I wait to the last available&#10;minute and then I always vote with the losers. Because, my friend, the&#10;winners never remember and the losers never forget.  &#10;*    - [Sen. Everett Dirksen](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dirksen)*&#10;&#10;Wise men make proverbs, but fools repeat them.  &#10;*    - [Samuel Palmer](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samuel_Palmer)*&#10;&#10;In the End, we will remember not the words of our enemies, but the&#10;silence of our friends.  &#10;*    - [Martin Luther King&#10;Jr.](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luther_King)*&#10;&#10;In the end, everything is a gag.  &#10;*    - [Charlie&#10;Chaplin](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Chaplin_%28disambiguation%29)*&#10;&#10;------------------------------------------------------------------------&#10;&#10;*[Peter Norvig](http://norvig.com/index.html)*">
</outline>
